Speaker: The best or worst thing about the weather in Chicago is that it’s always changing.
It can be very hot or very cold.
In the summer, it’s mostly sunny and sometimes cloudy,
with temperatures of about 84 degrees.
And of course, sometimes it rains.
In the winter, the temperature is usually between 29 and 14 degrees.
It can be below freezing (32 degrees) for weeks at a time. Brrr!
It snows about 38 inches a year.
In the spring and the fall, the weather is very changeable –
you can have all four seasons in one week!
It can be cold and snowing on Monday,
cool and foggy on Tuesday, and warm and sunny on Wednesday.
It’s a good idea for tourists to bring a winter coat, gloves, sunglasses, sandals,
and an umbrella when they visit Chicago in the spring and the fall –
that way they are prepared for any kind of weather!
But one thing that isn’t always true about Chicago is the wind.
Even though Chicago’s nickname is “The Windy City,” it’s not always windy there.
In fact, Boston has more windy days than Chicago.
Some people think Chicago’s nickname is from politicians who talk too much!